I'll say it again, so proud of the city that I love, the city that we love.
I mentioned the Good Stuff family, the stories that we're trying to tell now.
We stand up two things. We say, "Together we can, together we will, and God weaves,
now watch and work."
And that's what I'm saying here. I'm in awe, again, of all of the Good Stuff
that is at the core of the heart of the city that we love.
Okay, next up we have May Chen, inducted by Margaret Wong. Margaret Wong was
inducted into the inaugural class of the CIHF.
She's the leading immigration attorney in the country and has been a strong and
generous supporter of most cultural and ethnic activities in the city.
We follow Mr. Redna and Valerie, both old, old friends.
And before I introduce May Chen, I want to tell everybody in this room that Mr.
Redna and my family and girls and sister and I, we go way, way back.
When I first moved to Cleveland, I was young, I was hungry, I was an absent
nobody.
We didn't even have $200 in effect. I went through a horrible personal
relationship.
And the first person I met was the person named Albert Redna. He was so humble.
I didn't know he was that rich, and the daughter was the rich and now, but the
most righteous person in his home.
So he came, he said hello, and Rose, the pearl of the Orion restaurant, has
been this kind of, since day one, we are there.
So we talked about when the new mall started and the family, Redna family,
again, is on the board.
And we are closing on June 30th. So Mr. Redna gave Rose an awesome, awesome
send-off.
He has helped my family so much, so much, so much.
And I was a young lawyer, he referred clients, he would come to the restaurant
at night and say, this is how you do things, this is what you do, you know, and
don't worry about it.
And my reputation is, time goes on, we're talking about, you know, the old, the
Nazi people, and of course, his tuition.
And he'll tell me, don't you ever dare, what can I do? I mean, I do know, but
you know, we don't.
So I just cannot thank you. And I had some struggles.
The plane dealer was the, my little, my little, my little friend Alex Atreskys
here, they had such bad complaints about me and my racism, and of course, I was
too good.
So who called me the first time? Like, when Rose came to see me at home, Mr.
Redna gave me, he said, don't worry about the plane dealer.
You go on, you do this, you do that, and I came back up.
We have nine offices now, and I want to thank you. And I've set some horrible
things, and I say wrong things, he'll call me and say, I heard you said this,
don't you ever.
You are a somebody now. You're no longer 30 years ago who you were.
So Mr. Redna, I owe you big, big time, even now, to call us, I won't zero-beam,
my husband and I, you are awesome. And personally, that's such a big question.
But of course, as an old-fashioned Chinese with an old Jewish, I do this, I do
this, I do everything.
Oh my gosh, is he this? Is he that? My husband knows all that. So now let's
talk about it. We have to do better than Mr. Redna, not this competition.
Come, clap for me.
[Applause]
What a great honor it is for me to receive the Cleveland International Hall of
Fame Award. I do want to thank profusely, Mark R
Wong and the Cleveland International Hall of Fame Selection Committee for this
honor. At the Tenement Museum in New York City, there's a poll. People without
ambitions stay home.
Only those with ambition were willing to risk their lives and fortunes, travel
long distances, and attempt a new life in the United States.
I believe this prestigious award should rightfully be shared with these people,
immigrants and refugees, whom I have the honor and privilege of helping and
serving.
I'm constantly humbled and moved by their matchless resiliency, great
sacrifices, endurance of unspeakable pain, and remarkable adjustment to
challenging circumstances in this country, in order to realize their hopes and
dreams for themselves and them.
My work was simply to do the right and just thing. By advocating on their
behalf, helping them navigate through unfamiliar terrain to overcome barriers
here and to reach their goals.
My journey with them has been fulfilling, inspiring, and great joy.
In the early 30s, when my parents came to study in America, they were inspired
by their thought provoking professors, witnessed boundless opportunities to
create and succeed, and felt much warmth and support from fellow Americans
during their stay.
After returning to China and Hong Kong, they were convinced America was the
place where their children would thrive and succeed. My siblings and I will
forever remain grateful for the sacrifices they made for us coming to America.
My choice of profession to help and serve immigrants and refugees would not
come to fruition were it not for this country's great heart, for the displays,
oppressed, and marginalized.
Service, compassion, generosity, and human rights characterize the strength of
this country. Therefore, I will remain always grateful to this country for
realizing my dream to improve the quality of life for immigrants and refugees,
to become fully contributing and patriotic American citizens.
Joining me tonight are many who encourage and support and advocate for my
community work.
Asia CEO Elayto and her leadership team and Asia board members.
Cleveland Community leaders, Annie Hu of the Erie Journal, Anna Lee, President
of the Chinese Women's Association, Chia Chen, City of Cleveland Community
Relations, and Dr. Kevin Hartley from East Western University.
I want to thank my husband, Dr. C.F. Chen, for bringing me to North East Ohio,
where we work, where we raise the family, and we're able to serve the community.
And also I want to thank my children and grandchildren for supporting Asia all
these years since they were born.
My fervent hope is that we must continue to work together to foster and nurture
women, men, young adults, youth in our immigrant and refugee community, to be
meaningful voices and leaders.
North East Ohio can provide the resources and opportunities to realize this
most important goal.
Our own immigrant communities must commit to be civically engaged.
We must find time and learn to incorporate altruism, compassion, and
philanthropy in our daily living.
Finally, during these difficult times from the pandemic, racism, and political
divide, we must re-establish our faith in one another, revert to our country's
core values,
and continue to welcome immigrants and refugees who hold great promise and
growth and strength for America.
Thank you.